rent.com 2017-06-09

# Privacy Policy - Rent.com®

## Legal Notice

June 8, 2017

### What's New with the Rent.com Privacy Policy?

RentPath, LLC has revised the Rent.com Privacy Policy effective June 8, 2017 (the “Effective Date”) to add provisions relating to our Use and Disclosure of certain information you provide to us. The revised terms are found in Sections 3 and 4. 

PLEASE NOTE THAT THESE MODIFICATIONS ARE EFFECTIVE IMMEDIATELY FOR NEW USERS OF THE WEBSITE OR APPLICATION ON OR AFTER THE EFFECTIVE DATE, AND ON JUNE 18, 2017 FOR ANY USERS OF THE WEBSITE PRIOR TO THE EFFECTIVE DATE.

WE URGE YOU TO CAREFULLY REVIEW THE ENTIRE PRIVACY POLICY. BY USING OR CONTINUING TO USE THE WEBSITE OR APPLICATION, YOU CONSENT TO ALL PRIVACY POLICY MODIFICATIONS. 

**Click here to learn more about how we handle do-not-track signals and user tracking**

Rent.com is a technology platform owned and operated by Viva Group LLC, a subsidiary of RentPath, LLC ("RentPath"). The rental advertisements and related services accessed on Rent.com or through its tools, applications or services ("Rent.com") are procured and provided by RentPath and its subsidiaries and affiliates.

  1. ### Scope.

This Privacy Policy describes how we handle your personal information on the Rent.com website (the "Website"), the Rent.com mobile applications (collectively, the "App"), and on other related sites, tools, applications, or services. By accepting the Privacy Policy and the Terms of Service when you submit a property contact form on Rent.com, you expressly consent to our collection, storage, use and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy, including its transfer to and storage on our servers in the United States or elsewhere in the world where RentPath has facilities.
  2. ### Collection.

When you submit a property contact form on the Website we will collect your name and email address. In addition, we may obtain additional information from you if you register an account on Rent.com or choose to create a "Renter Card" or otherwise submit similar information to us on the Website or the App. While you can use many functions of Rent.com without being a registered user, certain activities may require registration. Once you give us your email address or any other personal information, you are not anonymous to us. In most cases, the information we hold about you is collected through Rent.com, but we may also collect information from private-label, co-branded and affiliate websites and/or from third parties with whom we have entered into an arrangement for such collection, or from their respective tools, applications or services ("Other Sites"). Accordingly, our privacy policy may apply to you even if you are not a registered user of our Website. Depending on the services used, we may collect and store the following personal information:
    * personal and contact information such as name, email address, postal address, telephone number and social security number;
    * move-in date and demographic information such as location, gender, age, marital status, occupation, the type of device through which you access the Website and/or App, and other personal and lifestyle information;
    * self-reported income and/or credit score information;
    * financial information such as credit card or bank account numbers;
    * additional information we may ask you to send or questions we may ask you to answer to verify your identity (such as your driver's license, credit card statement, and/or a recent utility bill or other information confirming your address);
    * information contained in "eMail Notes and Photos" submissions;
    * logs, contact information and other information about the communications between the past, present or potential renters ("Renters") and the past, present or potential lessors ("Lessors") using our or our affiliated companies' communications tools (see Section 5. Communications and Communication Tools; Property Contact Forms below);
    * guest card and Renter Card information that you provide;
    * lease terms, lease parties and other transactional information;
    * information automatically collected by cookies and web beacons on your computer (for more information about this, please see Cookies, Web Beacons and Your Privacy); and
    * information based on your interactions with Rent.com or the Other Sites and their advertising, such as search information, computer sign-on data, statistics on page views, traffic to, from and within Rent.com or Other Sites, ad data, IP address and standard web log information.
We may also collect information about your computer or other access device to mitigate risk and for fraud prevention purposes.
  3. ### Use.

Our primary purpose in collecting personal information is to provide you with a safe, smooth, efficient, and customized experience. We may use your personal information to:
    * provide the services and customer support you request, including confirming emails related to the Rent.com services, reminders and transactions.
    * contact and communicate with Lessors.
    * resolve disputes, collect fees and troubleshoot problems.
    * customize your experience and otherwise measure and improve Rent.com's services.
    * send you relevant residential real estate related listings via email, phone, text messaging or push notification on your phone (provided you have not opted out of such communications).
    * deliver targeted marketing, service updates, and promotional offers based on your communication preferences. (If we use your personal information to market to you, you will be able to opt-out of such uses; see below under Section 5. Communications and Communications Tools; Email Preferences and Section 6. Cookies.)
    * connect you with third parties that provide products or services related to moving or relocating.
    * make payments to third parties through the Website or the App, should you choose to do so.
    * request your review of a property.
    * compare information for accuracy and verify it with third parties.
    * measure consumer interest in our products and services.
    * summarize your information (including personal information) that you provided to us or our affiliates.
    * help promote a safe service and detect and prevent error, fraud and other potentially prohibited or illegal activity.
    * enforce our agreements, terms, conditions, and policies, and send you notices and alerts.
    * provide services as otherwise described to you at the time of collection.
    * prepare aggregated data, including for general marketing and analytical purposes.
  4. ### Disclosure.

We reserve the right to use and disclose in any manner, any non-personal, non-identifiable information including in the form of aggregated data that we collect by use of cookies and traffic data, or that you share with us through the guest card or Renter Card. We may provide some or all of your personal information, including email addresses, to:
    * Law enforcement offices, third-party rights owners or others in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to enforce our Terms of Service or Privacy Policy; respond to claims that an advertisement, posting or other content violates the rights of a third party; or protect the rights, property or personal safety of our users or the general public.
    * Other third parties who offer products or services that may be relevant to you, whose services you agree to use (e.g., online rent payment services), with regard to whom you have expressed interest or initiated communication through Property Contact Forms (See Section 5 Communications and Communications Tools), or with whom you have authorized us to share your personal information. (The information we disclose in this way will be subject to those third parties' privacy policies.)
    * Service providers under contract who help with our business operations (such as fraud investigations, bill collection, invoicing, telecommunication and call monitoring services, rewards programs, co-branded credit cards, etc.).
    * Another business entity should we plan to merge with, or sell substantially all our assets to that business entity. (Should such a combination occur, we will require that the new combined entity follow this privacy policy with respect to your personal information. If your personal information will be used contrary to this policy, you will receive prior notice.)

If you become a registered user, you can opt out of sharing your personal information by sending an email to [privacypreference@rentpath.com](mailto:privacypreference@rentpath.com).

We reserve the right to use in any manner and disclose any non-personal information that we collect including cookie and traffic data. Logs, recordings, and other information related to communication between you and third parties in connection with the services and/or other uses and purposes mentioned herein may be stored, maintained and/or divulged to those third parties by us on an individual basis or in the aggregate. Without limiting the above, in an effort to respect your privacy, we will not otherwise disclose your personal information to law enforcement, other government officials, or other third parties without a subpoena, court order or substantially similar legal procedure, except when we believe in good faith that the disclosure of information is necessary to prevent imminent physical harm or financial loss or to report suspected illegal activity.

  5. ### Communications and Communication Tools.

Rent.com communicates with users, and facilitates communications between users, in a variety of ways, including but not limited to:

 _Property Contact Form._ We make tools available that facilitate communications between Renters and Lessors by phone or email. When these tools are used, we may collect certain information related to the communication, like email addresses, contact logs, calling number, call duration, contents of the email communication, and (when notified during the call) call recordings. We may share this information with Lessors so they can manage their communications with Renters, and we will use this information to enforce our rights to collect fees payable by Lessors.

 _Send-to-a-Friend._ If you use our Send-to-a-Friend or other email tools, we do not permanently store the email address you give us or use that email address for any marketing purpose. We do not rent or sell these email addresses.

 _Email preferences._ We provide all users with the opportunity to opt out of receiving non-essential (promotional, marketing-related) communications from us after setting up an account. To remove your contact information from Rent.com lists and newsletters, simply edit your email preferences.

 _Email Notes and Photos._ If you use our Email Notes and Photos to a Friend tool, your notes and/or photos will be displayed for your friend on Rent.com and treated like other personal information you have provided. If your posting contains personal information, post only personal information for which you have authorization.

  6. ### Cookies.

We or our service providers may place cookies or web beacons on your computer when you visit portions of Rent.com. We use permanent cookies to provide personalized features, such as automatically logging you into your personalized home page and to deliver customized services, content, and advertising. We use session cookies, which are deleted when you log out of Rent.com or browse to a different website, to monitor and improve the functionality and usability of the Website. You can block our cookies by changing the settings on your browser (contact your ISP for help), but doing so may prevent us from delivering certain services to you.

We may use third-party advertising companies such as Cross Pixel Media, DoubleClick or Yahoo! to serve ads on our and our advertising partners' behalf. These companies may employ cookies and web beacons to deliver advertising and measure its effectiveness. Any information that these third parties collect via cookies and web beacons is completely anonymous. Please visit the Cross Pixel Media, DoubleClick or Yahoo! websites for more information about how to "opt-out." For more information about why we use cookies, see  Cookies, Web Beacons and Your Privacy.

  7. ### Third Parties.

Except as otherwise expressly included herein, this Privacy Policy addresses only the use and disclosure of information we collect from you. If you disclose your information to others, whether they are Renters and Lessors or other websites throughout the Internet, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of the information you disclose to them. Rent.com does not control the privacy policies of third parties. We encourage you to ask questions before you disclose your personal information to others.

Rent.com has links to other websites that may collect personal information about you. Rent.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those linked websites.

  8. ### Accessing, Reviewing and Changing Your Personal Information.

You can see, review and change most of your personal information by logging into Rent.com and editing your account profile. Generally, we will not manually modify your personal information because it is very difficult to verify your identity remotely. You must promptly update your personal information if it changes or is inaccurate. Upon your request, we will close your account and remove your personal information from view as soon as reasonably possible based on your account activity and in accordance with applicable law. We do retain personal information from closed accounts in order to comply with law, prevent fraud, collect any fees owed, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce our Terms of Service, and for purposes otherwise permitted by law.
  9. ### Account Protection.

Your password is the key to your account. Use unique numbers, letters and special characters, and do not disclose your Rent.com password to anyone. If you do share your password or your personal information with others, remember that you are responsible for all actions taken in the name of your account. If you lose control of your password, you may lose substantial control over your personal information and may be subject to legally binding actions taken on your behalf. Therefore, if your password has been compromised for any reason, you should immediately notify Rent.com and change your password.
  10. ### Security.

Your information (other than credit card information) is stored on our servers located in the United States. We treat data as an asset that must be protected and use many tools (encryption, passwords, physical security, etc.) to protect your personal information against unauthorized access and disclosure. However, third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications, and other users may abuse or misuse your personal information that they collect from Rent.com. Therefore, although we work very hard to protect your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain private.
  11. ### Minors.

The Website and the App are intended solely for use by persons 13 years of age or older. If you are under the age of 13, you may not use the Website, App or other services, or contribute any information to us.
  12. ### Notice to California Residents.

If you are a California resident, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits you to request information regarding the disclosure of your personal information by us to third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to [privacy@rentpath.com](mailto:privacy@rentpath.com).
  13. ### General.

We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the amended terms on Rent.com. We'll provide you with notice of the changes on the Website. Amended terms take effect upon acceptance for new users and 10 days after they are posted on Rent.com for all other users.
  14. ### Questions:

Questions regarding this policy should be directed to the following address:  
RentPath, LLC  
Attn: General Counsel

950 East Paces Ferry Road, NE Suite 2600  
Atlanta, GA 30326

or via email to [privacy@rentpath.com](mailto:privacy@rentpath.com)

Last updated June 8, 2017
